JOHN COLELLA

4 631 838 8222

♀ Brooklyn, NY

in

www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcolella

• https://github.com/jmcolella

Summary

I am a web developer with an eye for design, skilled in Ruby, JavaScript, Rails, Bootstrap and Materialize. With experience working in fastpaced environments, I'm a team player who can work efficiently and collaboratively with others to meet hard deadlines. I have excellent communication and organizational skills along with analytical experience that has proven effective in past projects and work environments.

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript(JQuery)

HTML5

CSS3

SQL

FRAMEWORKS

Rails

Jekyll Bootstrap

Materialize

iviaterialize

Sinatra

React.js

DATABASES

PostgresSQL

ActiveRecord

SQLite

TESTING

RSpec

Jasmine

Capybara

PLATFORMS

Google Maps API

Yelp API

Twitter API

METHODOLOGIES

Object Oriented Design Test Driven Development

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Italian

Projects

LOCALEYES

http://www.localeyestrips.com

An app that connects tourists to day trips curated by locals. Made in 7 days as a group project.

- Built with Ruby on Rails backend and Materialize frontend frameworks (Materialize is based on the Google Material Design philosophy)
- · Incorporate Google Maps and Google Places API to retrieve information for created day trips
- · Assist with set up of Google Maps integration into web app and logic behind pulling information from Google
- Use JQuery and AJAX for commenting, favoriting and communicating with Google Places API
- Responsible for styling and organizing inbox and messaging system between users; made use of the Mailboxer gem
- Assist with the set up of Facebook OAuth and implementation of Devise security gem

LOWER EAST SIDE FILM FESTIVAL

http://www.les-film-festival.herokuapp.com

A fake film festival website that allows users to review and rate films. Made in 2 days as a group assignment at Dev Bootcamp.

- Built with Ruby on Rails on the backend and Bootstrap CSS framework on the frontend
- Heavy involvment in crafting the app architecture
- · Style and organize pages for each film, which included sections devoted to posting comments and reviews
- Use JQuery and AJAX to enhance user experience with commenting and rating film entries
- · Tested with RSpec and Capybara

256 - 2048 CLONE

https://github.com/jmcolella/2048-clone

A clone of the popular game 2048.

- Built using vanilla JavaScript along with the JQuery and Underscore.js libraries.
- Use logic to manipulate DOM to display game for the user.

Employment

KATTEN MUCHIN ROSENMAN LLP

New York, NY Jun 2013 to Mar 2016

Paralegal

- Coordinate and communicate with partners and associates to complete multi-million dollar loan transactions.
- · Keep organized and compiled records of all necessary documents for various loans.
- Oversee the integration and training of new paralegal hires into the firm.
- · Analyze patterns in legal documentation to draft correspondences and other documents.
- Coordinate delivery of materials and assist with drafting minor legal documents.

TRIBECA FILM Acquisitions/Marketing Intern

New York, NY Jan 2015 to Aug 2015

• Generate transactional and revenue performance reports for Tribeca Film titles across various VOD platforms.

- · Compile master report of all past, current and future independent titles released as day-and-date.
- Organize VOD data into cumulative spreadsheets for analysis by VP, Acquisitions.
- Take lead on portions of grass root marketing outreach and research for Tribeca titles.
- Coordinate legal agreements and invoices for private or festival screenings.

MAGNOLIA PICTURES

New York, NY Jan 2013 to May 2013

Marketing/Publicity Intern

- Main liaison for guests via e-mail, phone and at the Magnolia office front desk.
- Compile press information regarding Magnolia releases and organize pertinent items in database for future reference.
- Research business contacts for grassroots marketing campaign and update database.
- Set up promotional materials, prepared a theater and ushered guests as part of a Magnolia premiere screening.

IFC FILMS

New York, NY Sep 2011 to May 2012

Acquisitions Intern

- Evaluate and write coverage on films and scripts sought for distribution.
- · Attend Tribeca Film Festival as a junior member of the Acquisitions team to screen and cover competition films.
- Organize and update IFC's electronic database of films using Filemaker Pro.
- Draft itineraries for executives and coordinate necessary accommodations.

Education

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK

B.A. Film Studies 2013

Thesis: The tradition of "mono no aware" in the films of Yasujiro Ozu.

DEV BOOTCAMP

2016

19-week intensive program focusing on competencies in Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails.